CARLIE SACHIKO CLIPPINGER

WEB DEVELOPER

|| CONTACT

(949) 257-3773

 $\underline{carlies a chiko@gmail.com}$

www.carliesachiko.com

www.linkedin.com/in/carlieclippinger www.github.com/carliesachiko

|| EXPERIENCE

InstaBrand (01/2016 - 09/2016)

Account Management Intern

Fulfilled the responsibilities of a Talent Coordinator, communicating and maintaining relationships with the talent and managing campaigns from beginning to end // Researched and implemented management systems for the team // Assisted numerous Account Managers with compiling data for reports as well as constructing reports and compiling potential talent for campaigns

Media Storm (for FOX Digital) (09/2015 - 12/2015)

Digital Planning Intern

Gathered data on existing digital ads and compiled it into daily reports // Presented findings on current digital trends // Maintained data sheets for report reference // Brainstormed advertising ideas for upcoming show releases such as Scream Queens, Bordertown, Grease Live, & Second Chance

Montage Hotels & Resorts (Summer 2013, 2014, & 2015)

Beach/Pool Attendant

Commended for providing quality customer service to fivestar clientele in a fast-paced and high-stress environment // Worked with senior management to identify potential client & operational risks // Achieved a promotion to managing the beach cart service, providing food and drink to the guests and public // Assisted in training new employees, ensuring consistent service

|| EDUCATION

General Assembly (11/2016 - 03/2017) Web Development Immersive (WDI)

WDI is a 12 week immersive web development course. During my time there I designed and built 5 websites, dedicating over 480 hours to studying and learning various languages, frameworks, libraries, and databases.

Pepperdine University (09/2012 - 04/2016)

Bachelor of Arts Integrated Marketing Communication

Lambda Pi Eta Honors Society

International Study Abroad Program

London, England

SUMMARY |

Prior to discovering my passion for web development, I was a full-time student, working my way towards achieving a degree in Integrated Marketing Communication. My history of work and experiences have instilled in me an eagerness to learn and an ability to adapt quickly to the situations I am placed in. I believe flexibility and an open mind are crucial to gaining the most out of opportunities. So as I venture into the development world, I am anxious to grow and build upon the skills I have already gained and am driven by a passion to make a positive impact wherever I go.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5 // JavaScript // CSS3 // Sass // Ruby // Ruby on Rails // jQuery // Bootstrap // Materialize // Git + GitHub // NodeJS + Express // MongoDB + Mongoose // OAuth // APIs // AngularJS // Heroku // Socket.io // React // Microsoft Word, PowerPoint, & Excel

RELEVANT PROJECTS||

Dots & Boxes | HTML5 + CSS3 + JS + jQuery https://github.com/CarlieSachiko/dots-and-boxes

Dots and Boxes is a classic kids game, typically played with pen and paper where each player is competing to create the highest number of boxes using single lines on a grid. Much like the development process, it requires thinking ahead. I used Javascript and jQuery for the game logic and HTML5 and CSS3 for the structure and styling.

Travlr | HTML5 + CSS3 + Sass + Bootstrap + Ruby on Rails https://github.com/CarlieSachiko/travlr-app

The Travlr App is a website I developed for the travel enthusiasts of the world, myself included. Here you can set up a profile, create a bucket list, and plan trips with friends. The primary technologies used were HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, and Ruby on Rails. Moving forward, among many things, I would like to implement an API so users can find their destinations faster and more efficiently.

Rooted & Wild Co. | MEAN Stack

https://github.com/CarlieSachiko/rooted-and-wild-co
This is a website I created for a friend of mine, who is
launching her floral design business soon. The main focus is
her portfolio of work, but I also implemented a shopping
element for added complexity and learning purposes. Some
features I would like to add in the future include a
scheduling system for her potential clients and integrating
her Instagram feed. Some of the technologies used include
the MEAN Stack, Bootstrap, and Heroku.